Hey everybody. Um, just first of all, I
want to thank all the players uh for all
their hard work, all their efforts, the
sacrifice, everything they put into it.
Um, I I tip my hat to what those guys
not only do during the season, but to
prepare to get ready for the season. So,
the utmost uh respect and appreciation
for all they do. Um, look, Dan and the
entire coaching staff, all their hard
work, everything that they they put into
it. Uh, want to thank our fans. uh they
show up support as they always do. Um we
are very thankful for that. It's just
very frustrating that we weren't able to
put together a more consistent product
for you guys, but we will get better. Um
but just it's so many like, you know,
our trainers, performance staff, their
care of the players throughout the
season, our personnel department. I
thought, um those guys did a good job
identifying some good football players.
uh death pieces that had to play large
roles. Um you know whether it's the
Mohamad or the Maddox Rockus uh Wheat uh
Lacy Stewart uh just just a lot of guys
they end up having played big roles. I
thought they did a good job of that. Um
but really um just the whole org. It's
really too many people to name but it
takes everybody to play to play the role
and give full effort for a whole season.
But uh look, bottom line is for our
standards, this was a disappointment.
All right? Uh when we when we set out
for this journey, for this season, uh it
wasn't to to match last year's record or
exceed last year's record. It doesn't
really matter what the record is. Bottom
line is if we're not in the dance and
we're not competing for a championship,
it's a failure. So, uh it's a lot of
things that we're going to have to take
a long hard look at. But uh before
before I look at anything, I'm look at
myself. All right? So I have to do a
better job. Obviously haven't been good
enough. And um look, I'm always going to
I'm always going to look inward. So
early stages, but already started to
identify some things that I can
definitely do better. And we're going to
collectively just have to look at
everything from top to bottom. Uh and
just really be honest and just take that
long hard look. Uh and really that's
that's probably the only light that may
come out of the this darkness I would
say is uh when you have these kind of
results uh you don't have a choice.
You're forced to look at everything long
and hard and truthful and honestly all
in efforts to uh improve our football
team and just kind of recalibrate this
thing to um just to play more consistent
football.
>> Questions? Just to drill down on that a
little bit, what do you what do you
think you got right and what do you
think you got wrong in the offseason
process of, you know, evaluating and
building the roster?
>> Uh,
in terms of get get right, I mean, I do
think that we brought in some good
football players that were able to help.
Um, look, obviously they weren't um
maybe just as a whole collectively just
wasn't at a consistent level enough. Um,
look, always hindsight. You can look
back and say, "Well, this wasn't as a
consistent level as you would like it to
be." Um, but you know, um, but bottom
line is we're going to be examining
everything. I'm going to be examining
everything uh with those with those
offseason decisions and our processes.
Uh but but uh but nothing really
nothing's going to change uh
fundamentally or foundationally in terms
of just the type of players that we're
looking for and uh what what our
identity is built on. That's still going
to remain the same. But but you always
have to evolve, man. You have to evolve
and uh when you don't get the desired
results, you know, you got to just look
at everything.
>> When you do look at yourself um at this
point in time, the organization has
regressed. didn't get to the postseason
this year. When you look at changes you
could make, does that involve
potentially more aggressive uh decision-
making in free agency and the trade
deadline?
>> Uh
that's that's that's hard to that's hard
to say without uh being faced with um
the dynamics of who the players are. Um
you know, it's it's a lot that goes into
those decisions. Um, I guess what I'd
say about that is,
you know, we we we work very hard in
terms of um well, I guess I'll back up.
I understand if you don't see a certain
amount of uh uh let's call it
transactional activity and
that's all you don't see. You don't see
the result. You don't see another player
added. You don't see the the trade. you
don't see the big splash signing. Um,
but our work ethic has always been high
and a lot of times really really all the
time is you have to put so much work
into making sure that you don't make a
mistake. Um really the the easier thing
to do is to um see a a name of interest
that you've heard of uh you think's been
a good football player and then you just
make the call make the move and then you
just didn't really put in all the time
and efforts to find out well why this
player is even available um or why is
this player not being signed back. Um so
it's it's a lot of work that goes. So,
that's not going to change. But, uh, but
I don't want to sit here and say that uh
just more activity is going to be the
answer. Honestly, a lot of the things
that we'll look at and a lot of things a
lot of the changes and tweaks and
adjustment that we will make uh probably
won't come with a headline. Um, but
that's not to say that we won't do
something that's in that splash category
or but um but I don't think it's any uh
it's not indicative of a lack of uh
effort uh work ethic. Um look, I think
somebody one of y'all called me at the
trade deadline and asked me, you know,
uh did you did you talk to anybody? And
I just kind of, you know, I wasn't
offended, but I think my response was,
"Well, why are you asking me now?"
Because it's a NFL calendar item with a
with a a title on it. You know, you
didn't ask me about if I talked to
anybody early November or October or
September or August or in June or in
May. Like the roster building thing and
engaging in talks with teams, that's
that's year round. But I totally
understand that that's not public
information. Um, and you can only just
go off of what's what's out there. But
there's there's a lot of work. So the
work is not going to change, but uh
we'll still be looking at everything.
>> Uh some of the health stuff that Frank
was dealing with at the end of his kind
of career there. Do you wish there was
anything you would have done differently
to prepare for his departure?
>> Yeah. Well, look, a player of Frank's
caliber. Um, look, you haven't seen a
Frank Ragnoff since Frank Ragnau. So,
uh, never would have thought that you
could just immediately just replace him
and just hit the ground running. Um, you
know, I think we did the best we could,
um, with everything that we were trying
to do from a roster standpoint. Um, but
look, the offensive line in general as a
whole, um, it hasn't been ignored in
terms of like there's I know we've, you
know, drafted in 21 and then 22 we
didn't, but 23 we went late, you know,
20. But you'd be surprised about the
moves that we tried to do that we could
not get done um that involved offensive
linemen, whether that be draft or free
agency. Um but um but no, it hadn't been
ignored. We tried to do the best we can.
I was excited about the youth uh
injection that we did um go with. I
think it was necessary, but I I believe
I mentioned after we acquired those
players that, you know, there's going to
have to be some patience. Um there's
going to be some things that those young
guys hadn't seen before. Um, I do think
that those young players will get
better. But, uh, but just the offensive
line as a whole, um, whether it's the
interiors or the tackle, that's
something that's, um, going to
continuously we're going to have to be,
uh, urgent in terms of adding to about
this on Monday. I asked Dan about this
on Monday, just with Decker kind of
openly contemplating his future. What
lessons did you learn from last
offseason with Frank going into this one
with Decker being kind of upfront about
it?
um lessons in terms of just him
contemplating.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Just like a potential hole
there that you know.
>> Oh well, yeah. I mean, if it happens,
again, like I was saying, it's never
been ignored. It like, you know, it's
it's going to come at some point. Uh as
good of uh let's call it more veteran
offensive line that we've had in the
past that has been comprised of a lot of
good players. You know, at one point,
you know, four first round picks at one
point. um it's never been ignored, but
you know, you also you just can't reach
and just make a move just to make a
move. Um you can you can reach for a
tackle or just make a move for a tackle
and that that player is just not as good
enough of a replacement. Um, but no,
that's definitely, you know, I'm not
sure what Frank is going to, I mean,
what what Decker is going to decide to
do, but u, you know, that's not only
will it be have to be urgent, uh, this
offseason, but it's been urgent in the
past. Um, and you know, uh, look, we
drafted uh, with two years ago, we
drafted Manu as more of a developmental
guy, thinking that, you know, he's going
to have some years to take some steps
forward. Um, but it it would be
irresponsible for us to just uh to just
go into it thinking that, well, you
know, well, we drafted a developmental
player a couple years ago, he's going to
be the guy. And and I don't I don't
think
I could be wrong, but I I don't think
that we've ever kind of gone into an off
season with um a question mark or a hole
and um we didn't we didn't attack that
position with urgency, but sometimes
just doesn't work out as well as we want
to. in the offseason did you learn that
Frank was retiring?
>> Well, I heard two Franks. So, go ahead.
>> I'm just wondering at what point in the
offseason did you learn that Frank was
retiring?
>> Uh, it was uh it was after the draft.
Um, it was that was when he officially
told us that, you know, like I'm not I'm
I'm not going to do it. I can't
remember. It was it may have been some
point in in late May or something like
like like that, but that's when he gave
us the final stop. Now, not saying that
the thoughts weren't swirling, you know,
not saying that there was no breadcrumbs
or anything like that, but um but and
even with breadcrumbs of it, you know,
but not knowing exactly what he was
going to do. Um you know, again, it was
something that we knew that we needed to
prepare for because we didn't know which
way it was going to tip. Brad, have you
guys maintained contact with Frank since
the failed physical? And is there any
chance that he gets healthy and attempts
another comeback for next season?
>> No, you know, after that whole thing,
um, you know, we just kind of just, um,
went our separate ways. I'm sure a lot
of the guys still um, you know, keep
contact with him. But, um, no, just
nothing in concrete about, you know,
seeing if he wants to give it a go
again. Brad, as you
>> you've been in every process with you
and Dan Campbell. Obviously, one of the
first moves you guys made was part ways
with John Warden. I guess just like are
you guys operating at a timeline or just
how's that? Why did why did you guys
feel like the timing was to do that
right away and is in the timeline you
guys looking at maybe trying to
>> Can you repeat that one more time
>> with John Warden partnering ways with
him? Know how collaborative you and Dan
have been a lot of decisions just as far
as this decision like just how important
is it to get the right person in and
just that decision to make that move you
know right after the season to let him
go as well? Any insight on that at all?
Yeah. No, look, um, look, there's
there's in this in this business, in
these chairs, you know, you have to make
some really tough decisions. And, um,
look, um, Johnny Johnny did a lot of
good things with us this time around,
the first time around for us. So,
appreciate all of his efforts and
everything that he put into it. But, um,
look, you just have to there is a
there's a time where you just have to
just make a decision, especially when,
um, when candidates, you know, are
becoming available. um you have to just
make the tough decision to to move
forward and and and move on. So we
didn't have a we didn't have like a
predetermined date in mind uh or
anything like that. Um it's just you
know just kind of after some discussions
um you know just felt that you know it's
time to just move on and start fresh.
>> Organization looking for his replacement
like what are the priorities for that
that replacement? What are you looking
for? I mean, it's it's it's a lot, but I
mean, um, there there has to be um
leadership. There has to be uh detail
oriented. It's got to be uh com command
of the room. Um you just have to be able
to know that there's somebody that's
going to be able to um dot every eye,
cross every tee, and make sure that
nothing is compromised from a detail
standpoint, from a standard standpoint,
um from the start of the game planning
period. uh all the way till the end of
the week. And um that's and so we're
just we're just looking for that type of
person where other person has previous
experience calling plays or not. Um I've
I've I've been around uh previous
coaches that have not done it and did it
and you know um had a lot of success
with it. So I do think a lot of it is
you just got to just get in front of
them. Um hear them out, spend some time
with them and kind of hear hear their
ideas, hear their philosophy. uh do a
lot of vetting, as much vetting as you
can, and just uh make the decision. But
I think when you go through the process
of getting in front of them when you
know, you know,
>> look outside the organization these
days.
>> Absolutely. Well, we're we're looking at
everything.
>> Do yourself analysis and you mentioned
evolving. You guys are at a stage now.
Do you do you think maybe you need to
act not as cautiously in player
acquisition and free agency, train
deadline or whatever? Is it you at the
point after a season like this that you
have to be more aggressive in certain
areas?
>> Um
yeah, I don't I don't know. So you're
saying just what to define aggressive?
>> Um when there's a need, don't just
necessarily plug with the same guy that
was there before or maybe more
aggressive trading up in the draft or
trading or free agent signing. when you
when the needs that are there before the
season began
>> are still there the and believe me that
doesn't happen every year. This was the
first year quote unquote failure but
this year the needs didn't get fixed
over the course of a year. Could you
have been more proactive?
>> Well I I don't think it was a lack of
effort um uh in terms of uh being
aggressive again like I was saying
earlier I may have been telling John
that like there's so many things that we
try to do that just can't do. like you
mentioned the draft. Um I think I may
have said it after the draft, uh this
past draft that yeah, you might see just
the one or two or three actual draft
trades that were they're on record, they
were consummated, they were done, but
the attempts and the things that we
tried to do, um that's not that's not
public information. So just because
you're trying to be aggressive and
you're trying to trade way up, that
doesn't mean that that team wants to
trade way back. Um like how we we've
been been picking in the past. Um we
picking a little bit higher um this year
that you know you don't you don't want
to be in that position. Um but and and
it it's the same thing with uh with the
free agency standpoint or you know
trades. you know, you can call about a
player, um, but
he's probably a really good player that
that team doesn't want to part ways
with. So, that doesn't mean that you're
going to get him. So, that's why I'm I'm
not trying to not answer your question.
Uh, but I don't think that we've like
not tried to be aggressive or just being
aggressive just to say we're going to be
aggressive. Usually when those kind of
moves happen, usually there is a
deficiency uh that's that's clear and
that and that team needs to act on that.
And um and we we've when we've had
deficiencies, we've tried to act on
things. uh some of them just didn't come
together. But we didn't want to, you
know, settle or reach, you know, if we
try to do the the big trade or the big
thing and it doesn't come about, then
we're not just going to say, well, it's
just another player that we're kind of
warm on that we can get. He's not going
to I'm not sure how much he's going to
help anymore, but it'll look like we're
doing something, so we'll do it. I don't
I don't think that that's responsible
either. But um but you know, you just it
just takes two to it just it takes two,
but um but it's not a lack of um not a
lack of action being taken on our part
>> on the uh
>> the offensive line um center position
going forward. You said it's not easy to
find another Frank Ragno. I think we can
all respect that. But
>> um you know, how do you view that
position going forward? Whether it's,
you know, maybe taking another look at
Ratlage, is that a place where you
really want a rookie? Do you need a
veteran to to kind of compete there? And
then with uh Manu, I know you said you
can't bank on him, but you know, you've
had two years to kind of evaluate what
you got to start to look at. Um how
ready do you feel he is to at least
compete for that job if if Decker steps
aside?
>> Yeah, you look uh I think I think all
those are fair questions. Um look, a lot
of the I'm not trying to dodge your
questions, but
we don't have all the answers right now.
And uh and I have full confidence to say
that we don't have all the answers right
now. And actually, if we did have all
the answers right now, you should
actually be concerned because uh we have
not taken the necessary time to do the
necessarily deep dive analysis uh into
our roster, our our operations,
everything from top to bottom like like
we are going to do. Again, there's some
infasy stages things that we've already
started to look at um that, you know,
we'll just keep to ourselves, but
obviously um you know, Tate is obviously
an option uh for sure. You know, um you
know, he's he's done it before. Um he
did in OTAAS. Uh didn't think that he
was a fish out of water. So, and then
all the reps that he's logged this year,
just all the rookie snaps,
he may have played the most. He may have
played the most snaps out of any rookie
offensive lineman this year. So whether
he's continues at guard or center, um
but we know that he's an option. But
yeah, we're definitely going to have to
um continue to to to look for one,
whether it be free for free for free
agency or the draft or a trade.
>> Uh and just Manu, do you feel?
>> Yeah, Manu, look, he's he's he's he's
taken steps. Uh I'm not going to sit
here and say that we feel convicted that
he's ready to be a major contributor. We
hope that he is. We're just going to
have to see how he comes back in terms
of when we get started in the offseason
program, how he comes back in OTAAS. And
um and look, he's going to have to he
he's as always, he's going to have to
win a job, you know, uh he's going to
have to beat somebody out. And so, um,
as much as we're going to surround the
resources around him, um, he's going to
have to do his part, too, um, to make
sure that he's doing everything
necessary to be as good of a football
player that he can be.
>> And Brad, uh, Dan Campbell on Monday
graded himself a freaking F. How would
you grade How would you grade yourself?
>> Oh, I mean, whatever is a failure. I
mean, yeah, I guess F. I mean, that's
that's that's fair. I mean, not trying
to copy what he said, but it's it was
either good enough or not good enough,
and it's not good enough. So, uh, you
know, it's either a pass and we're we're
still playing right now and still
competing for a championship or or not.
And if we're not, then fail. So, that's
where I put it.
>> But, I'm not going to get into the
Dminus and all, you know.
>> What would have been the biggest failure
in your mind for this season? What would
have been the biggest failure?
>> The what what failed the most, I guess,
from your point of view.
>> Oh, just that we weren't able to play. I
mean, well, right now where we're at
right now, I'm here talking to you guys.
Not saying that I don't like talking to
you guys, but you guys know what I'm
saying. It's it's over and football's
still being played. So, that is the
biggest failure. Um, and that's that's
what it's going to be for our standards.
Look, in 2021, you know, when we first
were starting out and trying to lay the
foundation, um, us not being in the
postseason, but we made some strides
towards the end, uh, you know, provided
a little bit of hope, a little bit of
optimism. Um, but for where we're at
now, oh, absolutely. Biggest failure
off the back to your comments off the
top said you're always going to look
inward and you've started to identify
some things already that you can do
better. Can you share a few that have
come to mind?
>> No, I keep those to myself. Um, you
know, just from a competitive strategic
advantage, but trust me, it's it's being
looked at. I've, you know, I don't know
what y'all believe or think, but I I'
I've always been big on self assessment.
Um, if if something is not working,
okay, what could you have done better to
make it work? and or if something did
didn't work then you got to look back
and you know really take a long hard
look at okay like how did I mess this up
or what could I have done better in this
area or could I made a kind of different
decision that I you know it it's a lot
of different things but I'm I'm always
going to start with with my myself first
it's um after every single loss you know
that's that's the first thing that I'm
looking I'm not looking at you know um
oh this happened this ball didn't bounce
this way this that that and I'm like,
man, are these are these are these
players like are they performing well
enough and and if if they're not, then
you know that that that falls on me and
I I have to get better. So, that's how
I'm always going to uh look at it.
>> The uh the injuries defensively last
year maybe make it a little bit of an
outlier in 2024, but just over the last
couple years, the defense has not been
playing well at the most critical
junctures of the season. what can you do
on your end to to kind of improve the
level of defense that's being played
down the stretch?
>> Yeah, I mean, obviously, look, when you
lose some impact players as we did, um,
you know, it's you're you're going to
you're going to have some hurdles. Now,
I do think some guys came in and stepped
up and um but you know, a lot of those
guys we we brought in to be quality
depth and they had to play large roles
and be starters. But um but as far as
like and I think a lot of the the the
secondary injuries, you know, you could
say that equated a little bit to more of
the explosive plays in the pass game,
but um but late in the season, some of
the run defense stuff um I just think
that was just uncharacteristic. Uh we've
normally been relatively very good uh in
the in in run defense and uh it just it
just was not clicking. It just was not
consistent. But again, it's like I said
at the top, uh we are going to look at
everything. Um I'm always going to look
at players first, but I'm sure me and
Dan are going to look at players,
scheme, the whole thing.
>> Change your calculus of just how how
close or far you guys are from from
reaching the Super Bowl?
>> Say that one more time. like like how
how did this season change your just the
big picture view of how close or far you
think you are from this?
>> You know, I don't I don't think that
we're that far off. Um I I personally
don't. Um we we have a lot of good
players. We have a lot of good young
ascending players. Um we have a really
good quarterback. We have the right
coach. Um I I I do think that we're
we're we're very close and um and hey
look maybe that is some of the things
that you know um maybe that's one of the
items that needs to be looked back on is
thinking that you are so close and so
then now you start changing some things
because you only need this piece, you
only need that piece and you got to
feel, you know, and it's like no. Uh-uh.
like who's the best player to fit for
what we're trying to do that has gotten
us to have the expectations that we have
as a football team right right now. So
again, we'll be looking at everything,
but I do not think that this is a deep
surgery overhaul like T, you know, I
don't I don't I don't think that, but um
but obviously there needs to be uh some
adjustments made for sure.
>> You've been taking care of a lot of your
own. Obviously, y'all got nearly a
billion committed and guys you brought
in. And I know that's got to be
something that you proud of is just
signing your guys. You got a couple more
guys eligible for extensions. You got
Sam Leaporta and Gibbs coming up. How
big is that a priority to get those guys
taken care of as well?
>> It is a priority because they're really
good players. And um that's look, we um
you know, when me and Dan first started,
you know, we said we're going to take
the the path of draft, develop, and sign
our own. And uh I do think that that has
worked so far in terms of getting us to
this point. Um, so yeah, um, those those
guys are priorities because they're
really good players. They're really good
players. They're great in the locker
room. They represent everything that
we're about, but um, but yeah, so I
would say that those are all all
priorities. We'll just kind of we're not
we don't have a decision on timeline
yet, but yeah, definitely both
priorities on that. You know, you used
that no vacations sort of, you know,
analogy last year, right? Paying some of
your own guys. You couldn't take the big
vacations in the offseason. No. um with
Sam and Brian since the injuries
happened. Does that how does that maybe
change that? Could that free up more
money, more cash flow to use early in
the offseason, if you can push those
deals off to later when they get
healthy?
>> Yeah, that's that's that's fair to ask,
Dave. Um I do think that uh their the
priorities for those players uh have
have not changed, but obviously, you
know, more medical information has to be
gathered. Um, but you know, we know who
they are. We know what kind of players
they are, but you know, in terms of, you
know, um, them suffering some season
ending injuries and, you know, the
decisions that we got to make off of
that, there's just a lot more
information that we're going to need to
get, which we will get, um, that's not
going to be forgotten about. So, it's a
little bit too early to say that, um,
because of those injuries happen that
that's freed up to get other guys. you
could you reallocate some of that to not
that you wouldn't spend it, but if you
spend it in the fall instead of in the
spring, could you use that on free
agents to maybe take a vacation and and
address one of those those areas that
you think you need?
>> Yeah, but there's other players that are
not injured um that are eligible as as
well. So, um and then you have just just
normal free agency. So, um, you know,
the money is the money, you know,
whether you want to spend it, you know,
in in April or if you want to spend it
in August, you know, um, that's just
that's just what you have. Uh,
especially when it comes, but now
there's things that we're still awaiting
on too, like let's see how large this
how much this cap number grows or
adjusts and all that kind of stuff. So,
it's just a lot of information that
we're still waiting on to see um, to
make those decisions. Big question on
the philosophical this this kind of big
philosophical, but this whole thing's
been built on, you know, grit and guys
with chips on their shoulder and you've
you've managed to have a lot of
continuity on this roster and built a
foundation. You keep reinvesting the
guys. Is it hard to be able to still tap
into the the gritty mentality when you
have that level of of continuity and
stability?
Uh,
you mean like in terms of
when you get as many of them as we have
that do they
>> I feel like that's
>> you say like are they losing it? Is that
what you're asking
>> from from a franchisewide perspective?
Yeah. Have you lost a little bit of that
that edge that kind of helped you get to
this point?
>> Oh yeah. I I think that's a fair
question. Um, no. Like look those those
guys have gotten to this point because
of they are really gritty players. Um, I
think it's more discipline on our part
to make sure that we're adding that and
that we don't get complacent, uh, or we
don't kind of say, "Oh, well, we have
all these, you know, these stars that
we've rewarded and they're really good
players. They earn their their rewards
because they are gritty players and that
they are fits and that they have
performed at at a high level. But we
have to that's part of just staying
disciplined in our approach. And so
that's something else that you know
definitely going to you know make sure
that we got to take a look at and make
sure that we're staying disciplined
because in human nature you can uh you
know I think you can lose sight of it if
if you're not careful. So, um, but, um,
that's definitely something that, you
know, I know is on the top of my mind is
just that we have to keep injecting that
to that type of player, um, with with
because that's how we got to this point.
>> And Jim over here and we'll come back to
the middle.
>> Dan talked about on Monday adding more
competition, really emphasizing that and
the roster. How does that affect the
calculus as far as drafting kind of more
developmental prospects and taking
chances on those guys?
Look, as long as they're made up of the
right kind of stuff, um that's that's
that's really I think that's the main
thing that that matters. You know, if
they have the Yeah, there's a baseline
of talent that you have to have um for
for this league. But they have to have
the right temperament, the right
intangible qualities, they have to have
the right football character. uh
regardless if that's a higher floor
player, um whether that's a
developmental player, um if if someone
is going to be highly competitive to
add, whether it's a young guy, then
players like that, they they they they
can add some discomfort and uh and I I
think that that's that's necessary from
from a competition standpoint. So, it's
it's not really going to change the
calculus in terms of do we uh take a guy
that's a little bit more developmental.
he can be. Look, we took a developmental
player that is about as high motored as
as it can get and you know um he can
frustrate a lot of players in in
practice because of that and I I think
that that's a good thing. So um but we
just got to make sure that they're made
up of the right stuff. I'm more I have
my antennas peaked up that we don't go
the opposite, you know, and start
looking for, you know, uh this more
talented player that may not have the
other stuff. And so that's going to be
um a a focal point that we we're going
to have to have going forward. When
>> we talked to Kirby in December, it was
maybe the most dejected I can ever
remember a player talking about his his
injury. just what's the concern level
with the knee, especially coming off
obviously the contract extension. Is
there any worry that he might not be
able to play that out? Yeah, you know, I
I um you know, Kirby really wanted to be
out there, you know. Um Kirby, he he he
earned that extension and uh just I I I
knew how excited he was to
I felt like he's already shown the world
what type of player he is, but now that
he got the extension, I felt like he
really wanted to show the world why he
got that extension. And um you know,
obviously, you know, he had some things
that he had to deal with. um physically
and what what became hard was
you're trying to urgently get healthy
enough to play during the season and um
and and that's really the reason why we
waited so long to put him on IR because
he was making strides and progress at
different points of the season where you
know maybe another week or maybe another
two weeks and so um when you had that
last recent setback late but Well,
bottom line, I'm just glad that Kirby's
in a spot now where he's not trying to
urgently get healthy. You know, he's
going to have the necessary time to get
the rehab and treatment that that he
needs um to get as healthy as he can.
>> You guys feel something in the physical
process with that? Like after he signed
the extension that might have or before
he signed it, I guess that might have,
you know, I don't know, you know, made
it so that you didn't sign that
extension.
>> Oh, no. It just, you know, look, it's
it's one of those things that just it it
just it just popped up on us. And um you
know, if if we you know, it just
happened. It just happened. And um you
know, um it it it it sucks, you know,
when it happens like that. But um but it
does. So all we can do is just um is
just adjust and um you know, see how how
healthy he can get. Um I I know I know
he is and just move forward. But, uh, I
wouldn't I I I wouldn't call it a a miss
as if like we knew that and then we did
that, you know.
>> Should you have known it before you
before he signed it, you know, should
you have found it before when he did his
physical when you, you know, before he
signed the contract?
>> I mean, in a perfect world, yeah, that
would have been that that that would
have been nice. But, you know, in terms
of, you know, passing exit physicals and
all that kind of stuff, we felt that we
had the information and um, you know, we
signed him to extension and and this
happened and and look, I mean, you know,
early in training camp, you know, um,
when he was going going out there, he
looked like he was he was curvy and then
it just started kind of going down from
from there. But he did everything he
could. Um, you know, he was still a
productive player in the games that he
was out there from a ball production
standpoint. um which not even putting a
number on the percentage that he was
from a health standpoint but um the main
goal is just you know let's get him
healthy.
>> Can't let you go without
>> more guys Justin Rachel and what you
after that
>> can't can't uh leave this without asking
an edge question Brad um
took a lot of different bites from the
apple last year through kind of a
multiaceted plan. Uh Muhammad obviously
worked out really well. The the rest of
the collective didn't give you a whole
lot. I don't think any of that's under
contract next year except for Hassan um
who's kind of in that project ballpark.
So um what what did you learn from your
approach last year that uh can maybe
help you find that that guy to give you
something opposite Aiden this this off
season? Yeah, I mean it'll be the same
approach that we took last year in terms
of um um it the position wasn't ignored
um in the draft. It just couldn't it
just didn't come together um like like
how we would have liked it to be from
from a draft standpoint. Um but you
know, Mohamd played really really well.
Um I'm not sure how many how many other
teams had you know an 11 sack and a 14
and a half sack guy. I thought the rush
were good, but I understand that he's a
free agent. Um, you know, Davenport's
free agent, so we definitely going to
have to look and replenish um opposite
of Hutch for sure.
>> I'm sure you're happy with Isaac's
rookie year, but how did the lack of
third round picks sort of affect what
you can do in trade conversations uh
behind the scenes, if at all?
>> Yeah, you know, you have to always be at
peace with that when you actually decide
to part ways with that. And um even with
even when you're in April in the draft
and you're about to part ways with that
type of compensation, um you you have to
know that it's it's gone and you don't
and you're not going to have a third
round pick at the trade deadline. And
you you just you just have to understand
that. I do think there's other creative
ways that you can do to supplement a
third round pick when it comes to trades
with uh with future picks, players being
involved and all of that. But um but
that's one that you can't have regret or
look back on and you just have to be at
peace when you part ways of that
compensation. But uh but very very happy
with the growth that Tesla took.
>> Obviously there are a lot of factors
that contribute to to the stagnancy of
the run game this year, but just from
your perspective, do you expect David
Malcomery to be here next year?
>> Yeah, look um obviously I know that it
was a tough year for him um in terms of
the lack of touches. Uh it and I'm not
going to say that we went into it um
planning for it to be that that way. I
thought he handled it like a pro. Um and
so look, those are those are discussions
that we're going to have to have um uh a
lot more in depth in terms of, you know,
like what is the best plan for him going
forward, you know? Um is it is it
somewhere else or um whatever the case
be? But just really appreciate
everything that he has done for us if it
does end up going that way. I hope it
doesn't because we love David McGomery.
He's a he's he's a good football player
and um wish we would have been able to
get more utilization from him. I know
Dan feels feels the same way. Um but you
know, those are conversations that we're
going to have to have because got a lot
of respect for that player. um he
deserves to be in a situation where his
skill set can be utilized and so um yeah
would love it for it to be here but if
it can't be here um you know then you
you would have to just see uh what you
can work out the best for him
>> then we'll wrap up
>> have you and Dan had end of season
meetings with Sheila Hemp and has she
expressed any sort of more urgency for
you guys to push to get to the Super
Bowl and win it in 2026? What's been her
mindset for this uh for what happened
this year? Yeah, we we we have had
conversations with her. Um, you know,
keep keep that privately, but um but
always the hope is to get to a Super
Bowl and win win win a Super Bowl. Um,
you know, that that that's not changed
uh going forward this year. That was
obviously the goal the past couple
years. Um, so that that that still
remains and and it's not only uh I don't
even need to hear that from her, you
know, I'm the one that that's on my mind
constantly is um you know, having the
ability to put that trophy in in her
hands. Um so I don't I don't I don't
sleep well at night un unless that
happens. Um and she she's aware of that.
But yeah, we've we've had conversations
and she's she's always the great thing
about her is she's always consistent. Um
but um yeah, we'll just keep the details
private.
>> Just back to safety briefly. When
healthy, that tandem's probably the best
in in the NFL, but with Kirby and BB
both looking at injuries that could
impact next season and maybe even beyond
in the case of Kirby. How pressing does
that need feel at safety this off
season?
>> Yeah, it's it's a fair question uh
because of the obvious. Um again, we
just need we're going to need to get
more information from where those
players are at. Um, you know, and that's
really that's some of that's the hard
part of um when you make certain
decisions when you're dealing with uh
with players when it comes to medical is
that at the end of the day you just see
the final result. Is a player available
or not? But we get so much updates on a
regular a daily basis, a weekly basis in
terms of the progression that those
players are are making to and that that
informs the decisions that that we make.
So, um it's it's a little early to say,
you know, uh but that position is just
another position on the roster. So, it's
not going to be ignored. Um we always
want to build the most quality depth as
we possibly can. So whether it's safety,
um I felt that we did even even
expecting both of those players to be
available all of this year. Um I felt
that we took um about as aggressive an
approach as we could u building depth,
but again it comes down to what's
available truly um you know what teams
are willing to do. But uh but I do think
that the guys did step up. I I did think
that um you know I think we um were able
to to claim a young Thomas Harper that's
going to be you know you know you know
he's played a lot obviously this year
that wasn't the plan but he did and did
an admirable job but we know that he can
play he can be a depth role you know if
needed he can play a lot of special
teams I thought Ivante Maddox stepped up
when he had to. I thought Daniel Thomas
stepped up when he had to. Um, you know,
Eric Howlet when we had him, you know,
he stepped in and and did some things.
So, uh, but it's not going to be ignored
just like any other position on the
roster.
>> Thanks, guys. Appreciate it.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Heat. Heat. N.
[Music]